The future is history.
Twelve Monkeys is a science fiction, thriller,
mystery film directed by Terry Gilliam.
In the year 2035, convict James Cole reluctantly volunteers to be sent back in time to discover the origin of a deadly virus
that wiped out nearly all of the earth's population and forced the survivors into underground communities.
But when Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996, he's
arrested and locked up in a mental hospital.
There he meets psychiatrist Dr.
Kathryn Railly and the son of a famous virus expert who may hold the key to the Army of the
12 Monkeys; thought to be responsible for unleashing the killer disease.
James Cole, played by Bruce Willis.
Dr. Kathryn Railly, played by Madeleine Stowe.
Jeffrey Goines, played by Brad Pitt.
Dr. Goines, played by Christopher Plummer.
Dr. Peters, played by David Morse.
Jose, played by Jon Seda.
12 Monkeys is a 1995 American science fiction thriller film directed by Terry Gilliam from a screenplay
by David Peoples and Janet Peoples, based on Chris Marker's 1962 short film La Jetée.
It stars Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe, Brad Pitt, and Christopher Plummer.
Set in a post-apocalyptic future devastated by disease, the film follows a convict who is sent back in time to
gather information about the man-made virus that wiped out most of the human population on the planet.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on
December 29, 1995, by Universal Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed over $168.8
million worldwide against a $29 million budget.
At the 68th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best
Supporting Actor (for Pitt) and Best Costume Design.
It garnered seven nominations at the 22nd Saturn Awards, winning three: Best
Science Fiction Film, Best Supporting Actor, and Best Costumes.
Pitt also won Best Supporting Actor at the 53rd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of biological weapon, philadelphia,
pennsylvania, schizophrenia, stockholm syndrome, airplane.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.